literotica.com 2018-07-31

# Members.Literotica.com - To Use This Site, You Must Agree To These Terms.

### 1\. Introduction

1.1 We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of Literotica® visitors and service users, including members. 

1.2 This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of Literotica website visitors and service users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data. 

1.3 We use cookies on our website. Where cookies are required for the provision of our website and services, use of our website requires your acceptance of these cookies. Insofar as those cookies which are not strictly necessary for the provision of our website and services, we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website. If you would like to opt out of using cookies, controls are available via your web browser. See section 12 (About Cookies) below for more details. 

1.4 Our website incorporates privacy controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using the privacy controls, you (registered members of the website) can specify whether you would like to receive direct communications and control the publication of your information. You can access the privacy controls via the Literotica Control Panel: <https://literotica.com/my/#/user/profile>

1.5 In this policy, "we", "us" and "our" refer to Literotica also known as Lit Online. For more information about us, see Section 18. 

### 2\. How we use your personal data

2.1 In this Section 2 we have set out:  
(a) the general categories of personal data that we may process;  
(b) [in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the  
source and specific categories of that data];  
(c) the purposes for which we may process personal data; and  
(d) the legal bases of the processing. 

2.2 We may process data about your use of our website and services (" **usage data** "). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analyzing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services. 

2.3 We may process your account data (" **account data** "). The account data may include your username, email address, and any other information you provide voluntarily when signing up or using the website. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business. 

2.4 We may process information you included in your personal profile on our website (" **profile data** "). The profile data may include your username, location, email address, profile pictures, gender, date of birth, relationship status, biography, interests and hobbies, etc. The profile data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business. 

2.5 We may process information that you post for publication on our website or through our services (" **publication data** "). The publication data may include stories, poems, artwork, audio, comments, forum posts, etc. The publication data may be processed for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business. 

2.6 We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding our services (" **enquiry data** ). The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is either your consent or our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business. 

2.7 We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (" **notification data** "). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is your consent, obtained when you requested the information. 

2.8 We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (" **correspondence data** "). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website may generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you, improving the service, and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users. 

2.9 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others. 

2.10 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of our business against risks. 

2.11 In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. 

2.12 Please do not supply any other person's personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so. 

### 3\. Automated decision-making

3.1 We do not believe that we use your personal data for the purposes of automated decision-making in relation to **significant consequences** as defined in the GDPR.

## 4\. Providing your personal data to others

4.1 We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group of companies (this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy. 

4.2 We may disclose your personal data to our insurers and/or professional advisers and/or lawyers insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. 

4.3 In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 4, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. 

### 5\. International transfers of your personal data (for EU residents)

5.1 In this Section 5, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). 

5.2 We and our other group companies have our main offices and facilities located in The United States of America, not the EU. 

5.3 The hosting facilities for our website are situated in The United States of America. Your data will be stored in accordance with GDPR regulations, to the best of our ability as a non-EU company, however data storage and processing will be done inside of the United States of America. 

5.4 You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such public personal data by others. 

### 6\. Retaining and deleting personal data

6.1 This Section 6 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data. 

6.2 Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes. 

6.3 We will retain your personal data as follows:  
(a) Usage, account data, profile data, and publication data will be retained for a maximum of 12 months after you notify us that you want to cancel your account;  
(b) Log Data will be retained for a maximum of 2 years - or we will retain the log data longer but remove any common account identifiers such as your username and email address within a 2 year period. 

6.4 In some cases it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. In such cases, we will determine the period of retention based on our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users. 

6.5 Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, including all relevant laws of the United States of America, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. 

### 7\. Amendments

7.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website. 

7.2 You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy. 

7.3 We may, at our discretion, choose to notify you of significant changes to this policy by email or through the private messaging system on our website. 

### 8\. Your rights

8.1 In this Section 8, we have summarized the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights. 

8.2 Your principal rights under data protection law are:  
(a) the right to access;  
(b) the right to rectification;  
(c) the right to erasure;  
(d) the right to restrict processing;  
(e) the right to object to processing;  
(f) the right to data portability;  
(g) the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and  
(h) the right to withdraw consent. 

8.3 You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. You can access your personal profile data by visiting the Literotica Control Panel when logged into our website: <https://literotica.com/my/#/user/profile>

8.4 You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed. 

8.5 In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. 

8.6 In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest. 

8.7 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. 

8.8 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose. 

8.9 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest. 

8.10 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:  
(a) consent; or  
(b) that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.  

8.11 If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU state or U.S. state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement. 

8.12 Please be aware that Literotica is based in the United States of America and various U.S. laws may supersede or conflict with GDPR regulations. In cases where different regulations may be in conflict with each other, we will do our best to work with you to resolve your issues and/or concerns. 

8.13 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal. 

8.14 You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data email notice to us (info [at] literotica.com) in addition to the other methods specified in this Section 8]. 

### 9\. Third party websites

9.1 Our website includes hyperlinks to, and details of, third party websites.

9.2 We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the privacy policies and practices of third parties. 

### 10\. Personal data of children is prohibited

10.1 Our website and services are targeted at persons over the age of 18.

10.2 If we have reason to believe that we hold personal data of a person under that age in our databases, we will delete that personal data. 

10.3 If you have reason to believe that a person under the age of 18 has registered for, or posted data on, our website, please report that user to us so that their personal data can be removed. 

### 11\. Updating information

11.1 Please let us know if the personal information that we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated. 

### 12\. About cookies

12.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. 

12.2 Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed. 

12.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies. 

### 14\. Cookies that we use

14.1 We use cookies for the following purposes:  
(a) authentication - we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website.  
(b) status - we use cookies [to help us to determine if you are logged into our website.  
(c) personalization - we use cookies to store information about your preferences and to personalize the website for you.  
(d) security - we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally.  
(e) advertising - we use cookies [to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you.  
(f) analysis - we use cookies to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services.  
(g) cookie consent - we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally. 

### 15\. Cookies used by our service providers

15.1 Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website. 

15.2 We may use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

### 16\. Managing cookies

16.1 Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:  
(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);  
(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);  
(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);  
(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);  
(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and  
(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge). 

16.2 Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites including Literotica. 

16.3 If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website. 

### 17\. Cookie preferences

17.1 You can manage your preferences relating to the use of cookies on our website by adjusting the settings in your browser, as shown in section 16.1 above. 

### 18\. Our details

18.1 This website is owned and operated by Literotica, also known as Lit Online.

18.2 We are registered in The United States of America

18.3 Our principal place of business is in Delaware, USA.

18.4 You can contact us:  
(a) by post: ****  
(b) using our website contact form:[https://www.literotica.com/stories/memberpage.php?uid=81387&page=contact](https://www.literotica.com/stories/memberpage.php?uid=81387&page=contact)  
(c) by email: info [at] literotica.com 

### 19\. Representation within the European Union

19.1 Literotica is operated and hosted within the United States of America and does not have a representative, hosting, or any offices in the European Union. We are doing our best to comply with all GDPR regulations for our EU-based members and visitors. If you need to contact us regarding privacy issues, including those specific to users in the EU, please contact our American office as shown in section 18 above. 

### 20\. California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

20.1 Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.  
As part of the California Online Privacy Protection Act, registered users of our site may make changes to their information at anytime by logging into their control panel and going to the "Edit Profile" page.

### 21\. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

21.1 We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. All of our website, products and services are all restricted to people who are at least 18 years old or older. 

### 22\. Additional Privacy Questions or Concerns

22.1 If you have any additional questions or concerns relating to privacy at Literotica, please contact us anytime using the email address or contact form listed in section 18 above.  
Thank you.
